Guide to the Leslie Brown Papers, 1936-2016 and undated RL.11750
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Leslie Brown papers
1936-2016 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Brown, Leslie, 1954-
RL.11750
24.3 Linear Feet
6.71 Gigabytes
Leslie Brown was a Professor of History at Williams College, Williamstown, MA. She was born in 1954 and died in 2016. The Leslie Brown papers span the years 1936-2016 and undated and cover her entire career as a historian, from her doctoral training to her final position at Williams College. There is also extensive information regarding her professional interest in African-American history and the preparation of oral histories. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Interviews, Research/subject files, Course Materials, Academia, and Publications.
Biographical / Historical
Leslie Brown was born in 1954 in New York City and was raised in Albany, N.Y. She was a Professor of History at Williams College, Williamstown, MA (2008-2016). She also taught History and African and African-American Studies at Washington University, St. Louis, MO (1999-2008), and History and Women's and Gender Studies at the University of Missouri--St. Louis (1997-1999). She served as Co-Coordinator for "Behind the Veil: Documenting African American Life in the Jim Crow South," Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University (1990-1995). Her first book, Upbuilding Black Durham: Gender, Class, and Black Community Development in the Jim Crow South, won the Organization of American Historians' Frederick Jackson Turner Award. She and Anne Valk, her life partner, co-authored Living with Jim Crow: African American Women and Memories of the Jim Crow South in 2010 which won the Oral History Association's Biennial Book Award. Brown died from leukemia in 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
Access note. Collection contains fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
Conditions Governing Access
Access note. Collection contains electronic records that require special equipment. Contact Research Services with questions.
Provenance
The Leslie Brown Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018 and 2019.
Related Materials
Behind the Veil: Documenting African-American Life in the Jim Crow South Records
Collection Overview
The Leslie Brown papers span the years 1936-2016 and undated and cover her entire career as a historian, from her doctoral training to her final position at Williams College. There is also extensive information regarding her professional interest in African-American history and the preparation of oral histories, especially those related to the Behind the Veil project at Duke University's Center for Documentary Studies. The Interviews series includes those conducted privately by Brown as well as those from various institutions that she used in her research. There are typescripts and audiocassettes. The Research/Subject files series focuses on her courses and publications, with a particular focus on Durham, NC, African-American organizations, and well-known individuals. A few research items predate Brown's birth. The Course Materials series contains subject and course files she used in her teaching, with an emphasis on African-American studies and oral histories. The Academia series provides information regarding her preparation as a historian, as well as material related to her job talks and lectures, professional activities, and book projects. The Publications series provides various publications related to African-American history, both privately published and from the popular press.
African American college teachers; African American women -- Education (Higher); African Americans -- History; African Americans -- Study and teaching; College teachers; Historians -- United States; Women historians -- United States; History -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; oral histories (literary works); Oral history -- Study and teaching; Scholars -- United States; Durham (N.C.) -- History; Audiocassettes; Brown, Leslie, 1954-; Williams College -- Faculty; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.) -- Faculty; University of Missouri--St. Louis -- Faculty; Behind the Veil Project; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
- Correspondence, 1996-1998 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  Leslie Brown did not include physical copies of her correspondence with her papers, and only a limited number of electronic copies. The electronic records contain personal and professional correspondence, some documents and letters related to the Southern Historical Association, and biographical statements.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access restricted. Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - Correspondence, 1996-1998; undated; 96 files, 4 folders, 1.48 MB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0004)
    WordPerfect files; Personal and professional correspondence, some documents and letters related to the Southern Historical Association, biographical statements
  - Course materials and correspondence, 1996-1998; undated; 136 files, 3 folders, 858 KB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0008)
    WordPerfect and Libre Office files, includes syllabi, assignments, lecture notes, reading lists, and exams for African-American and oral history courses, along with professional correspondence. Some file formats may not be supported.
- Interviews, 1975-2001 and undated
  Includes interviews conducted privately by Leslie Brown, as well as those conducted by others, primarily for institutions, including the Duke University Center for Documentary Studies, the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Southern Oral History Program, the Missouri Historical Society, and the North Carolina Center for the Study of Black History at Hayti Heritage Center. Some interviews are marked with Brown's research notes. There are transcripts and audiocassettes.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  RESTRICTED: Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
  - Adams, Robinson, and Thompson (1 of 2), Charlotte- Chris Stewart and Bill Crumpton, 1993 June 8 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0018)
  - Adams, Robinson, and Thompson (2 of 2), Charlotte- Chris Stewart and Bill Crumpton, 1993 June 8 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0019)
  - Lou Emma Allen, Greenwood, MS- Ortiz, 1995 July 25 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0020)
  - Ann Atwater, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0043)
  - Bailey, Mary (SOHP), 1979 (Box 1)
  - Barbee, Annie, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Russel Blount, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0046)
  - Russel Blount, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0047)
  - BTV [Behind the Veil]: Notes on Interviews, undated (Box 17)
  - Ernestine Bynum, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0054)
  - Ernestine Bynum, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0055)
  - Ila Blue, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0093)
  - Ila Blue, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0094)
  - Blue, Ila and Quigless, Milton, 1995; undated (Box 1)
  - Braswell, Martha, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Harriet Brinkley, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0048)
  - Harriet Brinkley, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0049)
  - Brodie, Arthur, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Brodie, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0050)
  - Arthur Brodie, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0051)
  - BTV [Behind the Veil] Undergraduate Club, Intv. with Ernestine Bynom by Kimberly Councie (NCCU), Durham, NC, 1994 April 17 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0078)
  - BTV Undergraduate Club, Intv. with Charles B. Noel by Valerie Bellomy, Durham, NC, 1994 March 10 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0081)
  - Bryant, Artelia, undated (Box 1)
  - Artelia Bryant, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0052)
  - Artelia Bryant, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0053)
  - Caesar, Hallie, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Willie Cherry, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0056)
  - Children's Bureau Reports, undated (Box 1)
  - Clark, Chester and Roxanna, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Clemens, Josephine, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Intv. 1 with Josephine Clemens 11:00 am, 1991 February 15 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0107)
  - William Clement, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0057)
  - Community Stories, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Manuel Crockett, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0059)
  - Manuel Crockett, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0060)
  - Davis, Jr., Julius, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Willie Davis, Jr., Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0061)
  - Willie Davis, Jr., Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0062)
  - Joseph A. Delanie, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0102)
  - Joseph A. Delanie, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0104)
  - Mary Dent (1 of 2), New Bern, NC, Intv. by Karen Ferguson, 1995 July 26 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0044)
  - Mary Dent (2 of 2), New Bern, NC, Intv. by Karen Ferguson, 1995 July 26 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0045)
  - Anne Duncan, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0082)
  - Anne Duncan, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0083)
  - Vivian Edmonds, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0084)
  - Eyes of a Child interviews, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Faulk, Marie, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Annie Marie Faulk, Intv. by Lesie Brown, Durham, NC, 1995 September 24 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0022)
  - Fitts, Howard, undated (Box 1)
  - Fitts, Jr., Howard, undated (Box 1)
  - Howard Fitts, Jr., Durham (1 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0085)
  - Howard Fitts, Jr., Durham (2 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0086)
  - Howard Fitts, Jr., Durham (3 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0087)
  - Fresh Air with Terry Gross, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0111)
  - York Garrett, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0088)
  - York Garrett, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0089)
  - Garrett, Jr., York, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Goodwin, Margaret Kenedy, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Maragret Kennedy Goodwin (1 of 2), Durham, NC, Intv. by Lesie Brown, 1995 December 22 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0108)
  - Maragret Kennedy Goodwin (2 of 2), Durham, NC, Intv. by Lesie Brown, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0109)
  - Maragret Kennedy Goodwin by Terry Williams Video, NC Ctr for Study of Blk History, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0110)
  - Ara Green, Leland, MS- Ortiz, 1995 July 26 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0021)
  - Harris, Mabel, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Mable Harris (1 of 2), Durham, NC Intv. by Leslie Brown, 1995 October 27 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0016)
  - Mable Harris (2 of 2), 1995 October 27 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0017)
  - Collins Hinton, Durham, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0090)
  - Sadie Hughley, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0091)
  - Sadie Hughley, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0092)
  - Bernice Ingram, Durham, NC, Intv. by Leslie Brown, 1995 November 14 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0068)
  - Johnson, Georgia Beasley, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Jones, Dorothy, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Jones, ?, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Wm J. Kennedy Jr. Papers (1 of 3), NC Ctr for Study of Blk History, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0112)
  - Wm J. Kennedy Jr. Papers (2 of 3), NC Ctr for Study of Blk History, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0113)
  - Wm J. Kennedy Jr. Papers (3 of 3), NC Ctr for Study of Blk History, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0114)
  - Christopher Knight, Durham, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0095)
  - James Lee, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0096)
  - James Lee, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0097)
  - Lee, Kristen, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Omeda Livingston, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0063)
  - Omeda Livingston, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0064)
  - Lucas, Julia, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Julia Lucas, Intv. by Leslie Brown, Durham, NC, 1995 November 6 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0072)
  - Julia Lucas, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0065)
  - Julia Lucas, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0066)
  - Lyons, Bettie, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Lyons, Theresa and Jan Cameron, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Theresa Lyons, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0058)
  - Emily McCandies, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0100)
  - Emily McCandies, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0101)
  - Vivian McCov, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0038)
  - Maclester, Johnnie, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Johnnie MacLester (1 of 2), 1991 February 15 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0074)
  - Johnnie MacLester (2 of 2), 1991 February 15 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0075)
  - Mack, Charlie, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Mabry, Corine, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Calvin Malone, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0098)
  - Calvin Malone, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0099)
  - Miller, Dora, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Horace Mimms, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0039)
  - Horace Mimms, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0040)
  - Misc. Interviews, 1993; undated (Box 1)
  - Mitchiner, Reginald, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Malvin Moore, III, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0070)
  - Malvin Moore, III, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0071)
  - Verlie Moore, UNC/SOHP #4007, 1975 February 9 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0067)
  - Sam Owens, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0069)
  - Benjamin Page, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0032)
  - Mildred Page, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0031)
  - Parker, Florida, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. Loretha Parker, Interviewed by Corey Rogers, Rob Widell, and Shani Sellman 10:25 am, 1996 June 12 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0001)
  - Patterson, John, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Pearson, Conrad, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Pearson, Ferdinand, Summerton, BTV, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Phillips, Lottie and Riley, Janie, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Price, Hastie, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Hastie Price, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0041)
  - Hastie Price, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0042)
  - Milton Quigless, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0033)
  - Milton Quigless, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0034)
  - Raintree, Gwen, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Rivera, Jr., Alex, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Alex Rivera, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0035)
  - Alex Rivera, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0036)
  - Behind the Veil Interviews, 1999-2009; 345 files, 4 folders, 355 MB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0001)
    .tif and Word files, Behind the Veil slides, 2009, and Behind the Veil interviews, 1999-2007
  - Easter Sanders, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0037)
  - James Sanders, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0029)
  - George Scarborough, Durham (1 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0023)
  - George Scarborough, Durham (2 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0024)
  - George Scarborough, Durham (3 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0025)
  - Scarborough, Jr., Georgia, undated (Box 1)
  - Scott, Blanche, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Sep 11 Roundtable 4 pm, WBFL (1 of 2), 2001 November 22 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0105)
  - Sep 11 Roundtable 4 pm, WBFL (2 of 2), 2001 November 22 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0106)
  - Shaw, Catherine, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Shaw, Hollis, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Speight, Theodora, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Edith Stanford (1 of 2), Intv. by Kimberly, Durham, NC, 1994 April 15 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0076)
  - Edith Stanford (2 of 2), Intv. by Kimberly, Durham, NC, 1994 April 15 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0077)
  - Peggy Tapp, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0030)
  - Jennie Taylor, Durham (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0012)
  - Jennie Taylor, Durham (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0013)
  - Thorpe, Amelia Pride, undated (Box 1)
  - Amelia Pride Thorpe, Intv. by D. Jines, NC Ctr for Study of Blk History, Rev. Tulius Davis, Jr., undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0103)
  - Amelia Pride Thorpe (1 of 2), Durham, NC, Intv. by Leslie Brown, 1995 December 28 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0115)
  - Amelia Pride Thorpe (2 of 2), Durham, NC, Intv. by Leslie Brown, 1995 December 28 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0116)
  - Margaret Turner, Durham (1 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0026)
  - Margaret Turner, Durham (2 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0027)
  - Margaret Turner, Durham (3 of 3), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0028)
  - Margaret Turner, Intv. by Doris Williams, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0073)
  - Turner, Josephine, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Turner, Margaret Holmes (Box 1)
  - Turner, Viola, intv. W. Weare, 1997; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Interview with Dr. Charles Watts Tape 2, 1996 June 12 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0002)
  - Interview with Dr. Charles Watts Tape 1 at 10:00 am, 1996 June 12 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0003)
  - Watts, Constance Merrick Moore, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Constance Merrick Moore Watts (1 of 2) Intv. by Leslie Brown, 1995 November 6 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0014)
  - Constance Merrick Moore Watts (2 of 2) Intv. by Leslie Brown, 1995 November 6 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0015)
  - West End Oral History (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0009)
  - West End Oral History (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0010)
  - Clarence White, Durham, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0004)
  - White, Nate, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Nathaniel White, Sr,. Durham (1 of 4), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0005)
  - Nathaniel White, Sr., Durham (2 of 4), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0006)
  - Nathaniel White, Sr., Durham (3 of 4), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0007)
  - Nathaniel White, Sr., Durham (4 of 4), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0008)
  - Lola Williams w/ Grace Valentine and Emma Boone (1 of 2) Tillery/Enfield by Chris Stewart, 1993 June 28 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0079)
  - Lola Williams w/ Grace Valentine and Emma Boone (2 of 2) Tillery/Enfield by Chris Stewart, 1993 June 28 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0080)
  - Sandra Wilson, Durham (1 of 1), undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL11750-CS-0011)
- Research/Subject Files, 1936-2010 and undated
  Includes research and subject files for Leslie Brown's classes and publications, with a focus on Durham, N.C., and on African-American organizations and well-known individuals. Includes a few files on oral history projects.
  - 1890 Census, undated (Box 2)
  - 1900, undated (Box 2)
  - 1920, undated (Box 2)
  - 1920 Census (manuscript), undated (Box 2)
  - 1929 Fact Finding, undated (Box 2)
  - 1930, undated (Box 2)
  - "1936 Delegates to the National Negro Congress" compiled by Lori Husband, undated (Box 2)
  - 1950, undated (Box 2)
  - Af-Am Women's Historiography, 1993-2003 (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Journal of Fashion (1893), undated (Box 2)
  - Agents of Change: Black Students and the Transformation of the American University, undated (Box 16, Dvd RL11750-DVD-0002)
  - Annual Report, Dept. of Health, Durham, 1924, undated (Box 2)
  - Artifact (Shirley Chisholm button), 1972 (Box 2)
  - Behind the Veil notes, undated; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - [Bentley, Gladys], undated (Box 2)
  - Bethune Archives info, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Black Business (reference library and Black American), undated (Box 2)
  - Black Power, undated (Box 2)
  - Black Republicanism 1890s (newspaper articles), undated (Box 2)
  - Black Women Workers, misc., undated (Box 2)
  - BTV [Behind the Veil] Af-Am life in the Jim Crow South, undated (Box 2)
  - BTV {Behind the Veil] Education Chapter, undated (Box 2)
  - BV Charlotte Hawkins Brown Papers, undated (Box 2)
  - Carnegie-Myrdal Study, undated (Box 2)
  - Catlett, Elizabeth, 1975 (Box 2)
  - C. C. Spaulding, undated; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Child Labor Laws 1921, undated (Box 2)
  - Children's Bureau depts., undated (Box 2)
  - Club Women, undated (Box 2)
  - Clydie Fillwood Scarborough papers, Perkins Special Collections Library, undated (Box 2)
  - Columbia Oral History Office 2001, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Commission of Interracial Cooperation "Building Goodwill through Conference and Cooperation, undated (Box 3)
  - Commencement Addresses, Slater Normal (1900), undated (Box 3)
  - Conference in Race Relations 1944, undated (Box 3)
  - Dangers seen and unseen, 2005 (Box 3)
  - The Day After: a Town Hall Meeting on the 2004 Presidential Election, 2004 November 3 (Box 16, Dvd RL11750-DVD-0004)
  - 1996-12-01T00:00:00+00:00, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Dept. 7 Social Services notes--Raleigh, Conclusion, undated (Box 3)
  - Directories of School Personnel, undated (Box 3)
  - Documentary Studies--Prep, 1993 (Box 3)
  - [Documenting the African American Exp. in the Jim Crow South], 1993 (Box 3)
  - DuBois--the upbuilding of Black Durham, undated (Box 3)
  - Dukes (W. and J.B.), undated (Box 3)
  - Durham: A City of Industry and Education, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham black women "firsts", undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Book Research, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce 1915-1923, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham City Codes, 1947, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Club Women, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Conference 1927, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Conference 1942, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham County Chest 1923-1926, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Migration notes, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Obituaries--Women, undated (Box 3)
  - The Durham Plan: City Planning Commission 1927, undated (Box 3)
  - Durham Public Schools, undated (Box 3)
  - Early, 2004; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Education (Public), undated (Box 3)
  - Efland Home, undated (Box 3)
  - Elaine Burgess, Negro Leadership in a Southern Society, undated (Box 3)
  - Email, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Fannie B. Rosser Papers, Perkins Special Collections Library, 1991; undated (Box 3)
  - Farm and Home Improvement Durham County, undated (Box 3)
  - Feminist Research--Oral History, undated (Box 3)
  - [Feminization and Black Migration Papers], 2005 (Box 3)
  - Foner and Lewis--The Black Worker VII (1936-1955), undated (Box 3)
  - Foner and Lewis--The Black Worker, undated (Box 3)
  - Frazier, Durham, undated (Box 3)
  - Frazier, E. Franklin, "A Note on Negro Education", undated (Box 3)
  - Garrett, Nathan, undated (Box 3)
  - Gertrude Weil Papers, 1996 (Box 3)